JAYABHARATHI HARI

Machine Learning Engineer

Portfolio Website: www.jayabharathi-hari.com

jayabharathi.h@outlook.com | +1(647) 553 9590 | | Toronto, Canada LinkedIn: jayabharathi | Github: Jayabharathi-Hari-Vijayakumar



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Accomplished Software Engineer with 9 years of diverse experience in the Software Industry. Demonstrated leadership as Lead Program Analyst for 2 years and specialized in PL/SQL and Oracle Forms development for 6.6 years. Currently advancing skills with a Master's in Data Science, with practical application in AI–ML through Academic Projects.

AI & ML PROJECTS PORTFOLIO

Machine learning

T Computer Vision

TDeep Neural Networks

EXPERIENCE

LEAD PROGRAM ANALYST

Aetins KGiSL Ltd, India

iii 06/2021 − 06/2023

♥ Hyderabad, India

- Led a team of 11 developers to design, implement, and optimize PL/SQL & Oracle Forms solutions, aligning with business needs and improving system performance.
- Provided technical expertise to management and guidance on PL/SQL best practices, coding standards, and performance tuning techniques through thorough code reviews and evaluations.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams and clients to ensure timely delivery of new projects, resolution of production issues, handling change requests, and smooth deployment according to agreed-upon turnaround times (TAT).

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aetins KGiSL Ltd, India

= 07/2019 - 06/2021

• Hyderabad, India

- Deployed PL/SQL & Oracle Forms systems on-site in Dubai & Sri Lanka.
- Led Data Migration Projects.
- Proficiently solved numerous critical production issues.
- Successfully delivered robust new projects and handled change request projects.

PL/SQL DEVELOPER

Access Healthcare Ltd, India

iii 10/2016 - 03/2019

• Chennai, India

- Experienced in providing 24/7 production support.
- Delivered multiple data patch fixes successfully.
- Created Oracle Tables, Views, Constraints, Synonyms, Sequences, Materialized Views, Triggers for validation, procedures, packages, and functions.
- Implemented performance tuning of SQL queries to enhance the data conversion process.

JUNIOR SQL DEVELOPER

AGS Healthcare Ltd, India

iii 10/2014 - 03/2016

• Chennai, India

- Maintain and manage portfolios of key client data using Excel and Oracle databases.
- Collaborate with clients to ensure accurate information and documentation as per Business Standards.
- Implement and maintain internal data management standards for projects, ensuring compliance with laws like HIPAA.
- Collaborate with teams to automate various business processes, improving revenue.

JUNIOR CONSULTANT

Sutherland Ltd, India

iii 01/2014 - 10/2014

🕈 Chennai, India

- Engaged directly with clients for client relationship management.
- Collaborated with team to create dashboards, pulling data from various sources and presenting to management.

EDUCATION

Master of Data Science
Deakin University

iii 2022 - ongoing

PGP Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning

University of Texas at Austin

iii 10/2019 - 09/2021

GPA - 3.6 (Top 1% in the program)

Bachelor of Commerce Madras University

= 2014-2017

CERTIFICATES

☆ IBM ML with Python 🗹

☆ PGP AIML Great Learning
☑

SKILLS

Python, Oracle SQL & PL/SQL Machine Learning

SVM, Random Forest, Decision Tree, Classification, Regression, Predictive modelling

Deep Learning

Deep Neural Network, LSTM, CNN NLP

Transformer models, BERT, Tokenization, Word Embeddings, Sentiment Analysis, Text Classification, Word2Vec, Glove, Text Preprocessing

Statistical Analysis
EDA, Inferential analysis,

Hypothesis testing, Data Preparation, Visualization, Cleansing

Dashboard

Tableau, PowerBI

Cloud Platform

GCP, MS Azure, AWS

<u>Libraries</u>

sklearn, pandas, numpy, seaborn, Matplotlip, Tensorflow, Keras, nltk, spacy, gensim, hugging face, Beautiful soup, streamlit, pytorch Big Data Tools

pytorch Hadoop, Apache